Inventory of the Chinese pictorial collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Chinese pictorial collection
1868-1991
XX770
Hoover Institution Archives
1 manuscript box, 4 oversize boxes, 1 card file box, 1 scroll, 1 oversize envelope (8.6 linear feet)
Photographs and other audiovisual material depicting Chinese cities, scenes of daily life, various prominent personalities, and miscellaneous scenes of political activities.
Access
Boxes 1-2 closed; access images available in Box 4.
The remainder of the collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least two business days in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Materials acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at https://searchworks.stanford.edu. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
Photographs and other audiovisual material depicting Chinese cities, scenes of daily life, various prominent personalities, and miscellaneous scenes of political activities.
China--Pictorial works.
- 2 prints depicting Amoy, China, 1926 (Box 1)
  Access
  Closed. Access image available in Box 4, folder 12.
- Chinese scroll painting of the birth of Jesus, undated (Box 2)
  Closed. Access image available in Box 4, folder 13.
- U.S. Marines in China album, 1927 (Box 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Oblong photo album assembled by an anonymous Marine stationed in Shanghai, China, in 1927 to 1928. Consists of 108 photographs with neatly penned, concise captions below (on black album page) plus 132 uncaptioned photos. Captures street scenes around Shanghai (and perhaps also Tientsin) and the harbor; USMC headquarters and camp; leathernecks on duty manning machine-gun batteries, on parade, during rest periods, out on the town; many street scenes, including photos of locals (e.g., beggar, barber, shoemaker, merchant).
- Unidentified photograph, undated (Box 3)
- 13 prints depicting Chinese views, including the Great Wall and Inner Mongolia (Box-folder 4: 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Previously Envelope A in photo file.
- 33 prints of Peking (Peiping), China, 1936-1938 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  Previously Envelope H in photo file.
- 9 prints of the 1937 bombing of Shanghai, China, by the Japanese (Box-folder 4: 3)
  Previously Envelope I in photo file.
- 1 print depicting the staff of the Chinese Embassy in Paris, 1909; and 7 photocopies of prints depicting Chinese students in France and Belgium, 1909-1930 (Box-folder 4: 4)
  Previously Envelope K in photo file.
- 1 stereoptic slide depicting buildings in the French Concession in Tientsin destroyed by bombing, and one depicting the East Asiatic German Infantry sent to China to suppress the Boxer Rebellion, 1901 (Box-folder 4: 5)
  Previously Envelope M in photo file.
- 7 prints depicting rooms in Hotel Astor, Tianjin, China, where Herbert Hoover is said to have worked and lived, circa 1980 (Box-folder 4: 6)
  Previously Envelope O in photo file.
- Mao Zedong, Zhou Enlai, and last emperor Puyi, 1956 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  Includes 9 prints depicting the last emperor of China, Puyi, in a Communist political prison in Fushun, China, in 1956; 7 prints depicting Mao and former Chinese PM Zhou Enlai in Beijing airport in 1956. Photos by David Lancashire, the first North American correspondent to report from mainland China in the 1950s.
- Photographs of Shanghai, 1941 (Box-folder 4: 8)
- Postcards of Northern Chinese City, Harbin, undated (Box-folder 4: 9)
- Photographs and negatives, Shanghai, 1986 (Box-folder 4: 10)
- Photographs of Shanghai, 1991 (Box-folder 4: 11)
- Access image of prints depicting Amoy, China, 1926 (Box-folder 4: 12)
- Access image of Chinese scroll painting of the birth of Jesus, undated (Box-folder 4: 13)
- 3 prints of a house with beautiful artwork, given to the missionaries for kindergarten work (Box 5)
  Contents fomerly housed in envelope mB.
- 1 print depicting the Republican Conference held at Nanking, China, where delegates from 17 provinces elected Dr. Sun Yat-sen president of a provisional government, 1991 December 29 (Box 5)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope mC. 1 print is of the article in the Chinese newspaper Min-li pao, which reported the results of the election.
- 1 print depicting Chinese bandits posing in new uniforms near Chengchow, Honan Province, 1917, after they had been incorporated in the army of the Governor of Kaifeng, capital of the Honan Province; 1 print depicting Standard Oil Chinese agents at farewell party for Charles Forrest Crest, given at his home in Paotingfu, Honan Province, 1920 (Box 5)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope mD.
- 1 print of a cartoon by Tom Brooks, entitled "The Thorn," depicting Chiang kai-shek as a thorn in the foot of a Communist Chinese dragon (Envelope mE)
- MISSING: 1 print of Chang Hsueh-liang, 1927 (Box 5)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope mF.
- 1 autographed print of Dr. H. H. Kung (Box 5)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope G.
- 2 prints taken by Tony Wills depicting scenes of the Cultural Revolution, entitled "A Meeting Hall for Workers at a Nitrogenous Fertilizer Factory in Canton," and "Red Guard Posters in the City of Canoton Near the 'Friendship Store'", 1966 August (Box 5)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope mJ.
- 1 painting by Ching-chuk Yu, 1969 October 10 (Box 6)
  Contents formerly housed in envelope m*L.
- 1 print depicting the Diplomatic Corps in Beijing with President Yuan Shih-kai, circa 1913-1914 (Box 6)
- 1 print depicting the staff of the Chinese Embassy in the United States, 1868; and 1 print depicting the Methodist Episcopal Church in Shanghai, undated (Box 6)
  Contente formerly housed in envelope mN.
- Decorative Chinese scroll, undated (Memorabilia cabinet)